<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on </title>
    <link>https://lu-human.github.io/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lu-human.github.io/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital warfare in the Sahel: popular networks of war and Cultural Violence</title>
      <link>https://lu-human.github.io/projects/jelena-sahel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lu-human.github.io/projects/jelena-sahel/</guid>
      <description>The Sahel has become the scene of unprecedented violence since 2012: a period that coincides with the advancement of new ICTs in the region. The role of digital connectivity is both a uniting and disruptive factor in this networked warfare. This project investigates this relationship where it will focus especially on information flows on social media as a legitimation of direct violence, i.e. Cultural Violence. This interdisciplinary study will rely on Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Social Network Analysis to understand the ‘workings’ of networked conflict interfering in the increasingly violent conflict in the Sahel (Africa) and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Pixels to Purpose: Bridging Deep Learning, Computer Vision, and Korean Visual Data</title>
      <link>https://lu-human.github.io/projects/aron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lu-human.github.io/projects/aron/</guid>
      <description>As a PhD at the intersection of Digital Humanities &amp;amp; Korean studies, Aron is fascinated by how computer vision can enhance our understanding of Korea’s history. A critical aspect of this field involves the classification of printshops, which can aid in identifying the origin of printed documents from the colonial period. His project also utilizes optical character recognition (OCR) and object segmentation techniques to efficiently digitize and analyze collections of Korean texts and images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Tonal Distances using Dialect Tonometry (TBC)</title>
      <link>https://lu-human.github.io/projects/matthew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lu-human.github.io/projects/matthew/</guid>
      <description>Matthew&amp;rsquo;s PhD project involves using computational methods and cartographic techniques to explore, visualise and analyse dialectal variation.
The primary focus of my project is to develop a tone distance metric which allows dialectologists to calculate dialect distances on the tonal level. In addition, the study will address dialectological questions such as &amp;ldquo;do dialect boundaries exist?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;what are transition dialects like?&amp;rdquo; for both tonal and segmental levels, using Yue as a case study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing the History of Technocracy in Historical Parliamentary Debates</title>
      <link>https://lu-human.github.io/projects/ruben/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lu-human.github.io/projects/ruben/</guid>
      <description>Democracy is often said to be under the sway of &amp;ldquo;technocracy&amp;rdquo;: expert rule. Scientific institutions, experts and model have a tremendous influence on democratic decision-making, often at the cost of transparency and sovereignty. This research studies the rise of technocratic ways of thinking and the impact they have on democratic debate. It does so by mining and modelling millions of parliamentary debates from the twentieth century Dutch Lower House using NLP (Natural Language Processing) methods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
